Finding aid for the Getty Education Institute for the Arts, Grant Files, 1984-2001 IA10021
Institutional Records and Archives
- Special Initiative grants, 1986-1998; III.; 9.5 Linear Feet (12 boxes)
  - Special Initiative Grant Recipients
    - Education Writers Association:
      - Education Writers Association: Lisa Walker, Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-75)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Final Report (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Grant Offer Letter, June 1, 1992 (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Review (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
    - High Museum:
      - Curriculum Materials (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Final Report (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Internal Memos/Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Press Kit/Publicity (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Grant Approval (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Grant Offer Letter 1/3/96 (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
    - Illinois Alliance for Arts Education:
      - 3 DBAE Papers (Closed and Archived), 1990 (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Grant Offer Letter, May 17, 1990 (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Review (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - [Loose Final Narrative Report] (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Illinois Alliance for Arts Education: Nadine Saitlin, Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
    - Institute of Museum Services:
      - Diane B Frankel, Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
    - International Council of Fine Arts Deans (ICFAD):
      - International Council of Fine Arts Deans, Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - International Council of Fine Arts Deans (ICFAD), European League of Institutes of the Arts (ELIA) Conference 11/96 (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
    - Kenai Peninsula College:
      - Alaska Visiting Scholar Lecture Series in Art Education, Kathy Schwartz (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
      - Original Grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
    - LA Youth:
      - Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-76)
    - National Art Education Association:
      - 1980s:
        - Grant Offer Letter, October 11, 1985 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
        - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
        - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
        - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
        - Review (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Grant Offer Letter, June 20, 1990 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Review (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - National Art Education Association: Thomas A Hatfield, Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
    - National Assembly of Local Arts Agencies:
      - Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
    - National Assembly of State Arts Agencies:
      - Grant Offer Letter, August 16, 1988 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Final Report, 1989 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Grant Offer Letter, October 3, 1989 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Internal Memos, 1989 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Proposal/Budget, 1989 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - National Assembly of State Arts Agencies, 1997-98
      - National Assembly of State Arts Agencies: Jonathan Katz, Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
    - National Conference of State Legislatures:
      - National Conference of State Legislatures: William T. Pound, Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Correspondence #1 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Correspondence #2 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Final Report (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Grant Offer Letter, January 14, 1993 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Review (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Meeting, July 27, 1989 (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
      - Demonstration, Orlando, August 12, 1991 (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - Meeting, Boise, April 19-20, 1990 (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
    - National Cultural Alliance:
      - Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-77)
    - National Gallery of Art:
      - Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
    - National School Boards Association (NSBA):
      - Internal Memos, Year One (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - Grant Offer Letter, April 27, 1993 (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - Year One: Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - Year Two: Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - Year Two: Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - More than Pumpkins in October (Requests) (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - Review (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - Notes of Meeting, February 13, 1990 (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - 1991 NSBA Conference, April 12-16, 1991 (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - NSBA/Getty Visual Arts Manual (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - NSBA/Getty Visual Arts Manual Focus Group Report (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - Final Report (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
      - National School Boards Association: Thomas A Shannon, Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-78)
    - New York International Festival of the Arts:
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Correspondence/Grant Letter/a/p (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Final Report, 12/95 (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - The New York International Festival of the Arts, Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
    - Parker School / Sizer:
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Contracts/Grant Letter 1996-98 (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Progress Reports (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
    - Sacramento Regional Foundation:
      - Grant Offer Letter, January 31, 1989 (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Final Report (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
    - Teachers College Press:
      - Grant Offer Letter, November 22, 1989 (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Final Report (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Review (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Teachers College Columbia University: Special Initiative Grant, Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
    - Texas School Board Project, general file (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
    - University of Illinois Press:
      - The Board of Trustees of the University of Illinois: Bazzani and Porter Special Initiative Grant, Original grant letter, 1989 (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Ralph Smith:
        - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - Grant Offer Letter, April 9, 1990 (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - Review (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - Final Report (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, University of Illinois Press, Original grant letter, 1990 (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - University of Illinois Press 1993: (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - Grant Offer Letter, 4/27/93 (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
        - Hewlett Foundation 1994-97 (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
    - University of Nebraska Omaha (UNO) Center for Innovation 1998:
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Proposal (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Grant Letter (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Final Report (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-79)
      - University of Nebraska at Omaha (grants) [original grant award letters], 1998 (Box 2009.IA.38-02)
    - University of Tennessee, Southeast Center for Education in the Arts (SCEA):
      - Discipline-Based Theater Education (DBTE) Conference: (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
        - Conference Materials (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
        - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
        - Final Report (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
        - Grant Report (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
        - Grant Offer Letter 3/21/95 (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
        - Proceedings (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
        - Internal Memos/Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
        - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
        - Proposal Review (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
      - University of Tennessee at Chattanooga/(SCEA), Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Garorian/Performing Arts Conference, 1996-9 8 (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
  - Educational Research and Improvement (ERIC)
    - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
    - Correspondence (2 folders) (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
    - Budget/Proposal (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
    - Grant Offer Letter, 11/17/89 (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
    - Final ERIC Art Digests 1990 (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
    - 1st and 2nd Draft Reports (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
    - Progress Report #1, February 1990 (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
    - Collateral Materials (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
    - Final Report, 1990 (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
    - Year Two: (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Grant Offer Letter, 4/18/91 (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Progress Report 1 and 2 (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - ERIC Digests (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Trends / Issues Paper / Resource Review (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Final Report (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - ERIC ART Information Brochure (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
    - Year Three, 1995: (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Proposal/Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
    - Year Three, 1995: (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Grant Offer Letter, 6/21/94 (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Progress Reports (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Publication: "Lessons for Teaching Art Criticisms" (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
    - Year Four, 1996: (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Budget (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Grant Letter, 8/21/95 (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Proposal for 1996 (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
      - Progress Report (Box 2007.IA.16-83)
  - Goals 2000 Art Education Leadership Fund
    - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-81)
    - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-81)
    - Correspondence (more) (Box 2007.IA.16-81)
    - Contract with National Assembly of State Arts Agencies (NASAA), September 14, 1995 (Box 2007.IA.16-81)
    - Tennessee, Texas, Utah, and Virginia (Box 2007.IA.16-81)
    - North Carolina, Ohio, Mississippi, Louisiana (Box 2007.IA.16-81)
    - Minnesota, Florida, Colorado, and Pennsylvania (Box 2007.IA.16-81)
    - New Jersey, Nebraska, and California (Box 2007.IA.16-81)
    - Press (Box 2007.IA.16-81)
    - Satellite Town Meeting, January 18, 1994 (Box 2007.IA.16-81)
    - Grant letters Goals 2000:
      - Alliance for Arts Education/NJ (Goals 2000) (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - California Arts Council (Goals 2000) (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Colorado Council on the Arts: Fran Holden (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Florida Department of State: Division of Cultural Affairs (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Louisiana Alliance for Arts Education (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Mississippi Arts Commission (Goals 2000) (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Nebraska Arts Council: Jennifer Severin Clark (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - North Carolina Arts Council (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Ohio Alliance for Arts in Education (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Pennsylvania Alliance for Arts Education (Goals 2000) (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - State of Minnesota: Board of the Arts (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Tennessee Arts Foundation (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
      - Utah Arts Council (Box 2007.IA.16-82)
  - Special Initiative Grants Administration
    - Internal Memos (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Rejected Grantees, Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Correspondence (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Grant Program Generic Letter (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Grant Tracking Logs (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Budget Information 1995-1997 (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - General Information about Granting (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Foundation Center (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - California Community Foundation (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Internal Memos (Memos to Self) (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Correspondence with Potential Grantees (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Correspondence with Elizabeth Paul (Box 2007.IA.16-80)
    - Pending (NCSL), Original grant letter (Box 2007.IA.16-80)